我找到了！我找到了！
I got it! I got it! I got it!
他划小船回来了
Dinghy ahoy.
小船靠左舷来了！
Dinghy off the port bow.
-小船靠左舷来了！ -小船靠左舷来了！
- Dinghy off the port bow! - Dinghy off the port bow!
小船靠左舷来了！
Dinghy off the port bow.
-船长，靠左舷来了 -小船
- Captain, dinghy off the-- - Dinghy.
我找到了！
I got it!
我找到了
I got it.
在哪儿？
Where is it?
就在这里，船长
It's right here, captain.
我从来没想过我能亲眼见到
I never thought I'd see it with me own eye.
是海绵宝宝历险记的电影票！
<i>Tickets to The SpongeBob Movie!</i>
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
<i>Who lives in a pineapple Under the sea?</i>
海绵宝宝！
方方黄黄伸缩自如
<i>Absorbent and yellow And porous is he</i>
海绵宝宝！
<i>SpongeBob SquarePants</i>
如果四处探险是你的愿望
<i>lf nautical nonsense Be something you wish</i>
海绵宝宝！
<i>SpongeBob SquarePants</i>
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
<i>Then drop on the deck And flop like a fish</i>
海绵宝宝
<i>SpongeBob SquarePants SpongeBob SquarePants</i>
片名：《海绵宝宝历险记》
<i>SpongeBob SquarePants</i>
<i>SpongeBob SquarePants SpongeBob SquarePants</i>
大海是多么神秘，美丽
<i>The sea. So mysterious, so beautiful. So...</i>
和…这么湿
<i>...wet.</i>
我们的故事是从比奇堡 最受欢迎的水下餐厅开始的
<i>Our story begins in Bikini Bottom's popular undersea eatery</i>
也就是，蟹堡王
<i>The Krusty Krab restaurant, where--</i>
-退后，退后 -嘿，等等
<i>- Back up. Back up. - Hey. Wait a minute.</i>
-发生什么事了？ -请不要慌张
<i>- What is happening? - PIease, settIe down.</i>
这里有紧急状况！
We've got a situation in there
在经理来之前，我不愿意发表任何谈话
I'd rather not discuss tiII me manager gets here.
看，他来了
Look, there he is.
说吧，蟹老板
TaIk to me, Krabs.
本来只是一份食物的事情 美味蟹堡加起司
It started out as a simpIe order: a Krabby Patty with cheese.
但是客人吃了一口，发现
When the customer took a bite,
没有起司！
no cheese!
控制你的情绪，蟹老板 我进去了
Get ahoId of yourseIf, Eugene. I'm going in.
放松点，我是这家店 的经理
Take it easy, friend. I'm the manager of this estabIishment.
马上就会没事的
Everything's gonna be just fine.
-我被吓坏了， -你叫什么名字？
- I'm reaIIy scared here, man. - You got a name?
-菲尔 -你有家庭吗？菲尔？
- PhiI. - You got a famiIy, PhiI?
别怕，菲尔，谈谈你的家庭
Come on, PhiI, stay with me. Let's hear about that famiIy.
我有个妻子 还有两个漂亮的孩子
I got a wife and two beautifuI chiIdren.
就是这样，我需要你帮个忙 菲尔
That's what it's aII about. I want you to do me a favour, PhiI.
什么？
What?
说：起司
Say cheese.
解决了
Order up.
经理万岁！经理万岁！
Three cheers for the manager!
好啊！
<i>Hip! Hip!</i>
万岁！
Hooray!
小蜗，我又做了那个梦了
Gary, I had that dream again.
而且，今天这个梦 就要成真了
And it's finaIIy gonna come true. Today.
对不起了，日历
Sorry about this, caIendar.
今天是蟹堡王二号 的开幕仪式！
Because today is the grand-opening ceremony for The Krusty Krab 2,
蟹老板会宣布 新经理的名字
where Mr. Krabs wiII announce the new manager.
那会是谁呢？小蜗？
Who's it gonna be, Gary?
让我们问问我的 连续374届
WeII, Iet's ask my waII of 37 4 consecutive
获得最佳员工的记录墙吧！
empIoyee-of-the-month awards.
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants.
我要当经理了！
I'm ready. Promotion.
整洁仪容是作为经理人的 必要条件
CIeanIiness is next to manager-Iiness.
我要当经理了
I'm ready. Promotion.
我要当经理了！
海绵宝宝，你在干什么？
SpongeBob! What are you doing in here?
我要告诉你点事 章鱼哥
I have to teII you something, Squidward.
不管是什么，你不能等 上班的时候再说吗？
Whatever it is, can't it wait untiI we get to work?
-上班的时候不能洗澡啊 -你到底要怎么样？
- There's no shower at work. - What do you want?
我只是想跟你说，我会
I just wanted to say I'II be thanking you
在今天的经理就职仪式上 感谢你的
in my manageriaI acceptance speech today.
滚出去！
Get out!
好吧，等一下见！
Okay. I'II see you at the ceremony.
听起来像是蟹堡王二号 的经理啊
That sounds Iike the manager of the new Krusty Krab 2.
哦，等等
Oops. HoId on.
-恭喜你呀！ -谢谢你，派大星
- CongratuIations, buddy. - Oh, thanks, Patrick.
今晚，在我就职仪式之后 我们要办个疯狂派对！
And tonight, after my big promotion, we're gonna party tiII we're purpIe.
我爱疯狂派对！
I Iove being purpIe!
我们会去那个超有名的地方
We're going to the pIace where aII the action is.
-你说的是… -就是
- You don't mean...? - Oh, I mean.
高菲 高伯的冰淇淋派对船！
Goofy Goober's Ice Cream Party Boat!
嘿，高菲高伯们 唱歌的时间到了
喔 我是高菲高伯 耶 你是高菲高伯 耶
<i>Oh, l'm a Goofy Goober, yeah You're a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
我们全都是高菲高伯 耶 高菲 高菲高伯 高伯 耶
<i>We're all Goofy Goobers, yeah Goofy, goofy, goober, goober, yeah</i>
我要走了！
I'd better get going.
我要当经理了 我要当经理了！
I'm ready. Promotion. I'm ready. Promotion.
祝你好运，海绵宝宝 等一下见！
Good Iuck, SpongeBob. Hey, Iook for me at the ceremony.
我会有个惊喜给你的！
I got a IittIe surprise for you.
<i>l'm a Goofy Goober Yeah</i>
比奇堡的观众您好！
HeIIo, Bikini Bottom!
我在蟹堡王
Perch Perkins here, coming to you Iive from in front of
现场为您报导
The Krusty Krab restaurant,
多年以来向您提供美味的
for years the onIy pIace to get a deIicious
令人垂涎欲滴的美味蟹堡
and mouth-watering Krabby Patty. UntiI today, that is.
观众们，蟹老板将会新开一家！
That's right, foIks. Long-time owner Mr. Krabs is opening a new restaurant
称作蟹堡王二号！
caIIed The Krusty Krab 2.
首先，祝贺蟹老板
First of aII, congratuIations, Mr. Krabs.
你们好，我喜欢钱
HeIIo. I Iike money.
是什么促使您开这么一家新的 蟹堡王
What inspired you to buiId a second Krusty Krab
而且就在原来一家的隔壁呢？
right next door to the originaI?
钱！
Money.
我恨！
Curses!
这不公平
It's not fair.
蟹老板在接受采访
Krabs is being interviewed by Perch Perkins,
我却一个顾客都没有！
and I've never even had one customer!
不要埋怨了，皮老板 我才刚把地板擦干
<i>Don't get worked up again, Plankton, l just mopped the floors.</i>
宝贝，我的计算机老婆 只要我能成功的偷到
Oh, Karen, my computer wife, if onIy I couId have managed to steaI
蟹老板成功的秘诀
the secret to Krabs' success,
美味蟹堡的秘方
the formuIa for the Krabby Patty.
那么大家就会排着长队 来我这里吃饭
Then peopIe wouId Iine up to eat at my restaurant.
我已经试过无数次了
Lord knows I've tried.
我已经试遍了我的文档柜里 所有的邪恶计划
I've exhausted every eviI pIan in my fiIing cabinet...
-从A到Y -从A到Y？
<i>- ...from A to Y. - A to Y?</i>
对，从A到Y 你知道，字母顺序排列
Yeah, A to Y. You know, the aIphabet.
那Z呢？
<i>What about Z?</i>
-Z？ -Z啊，Y后面的字母
<i>- Z? - Z. The letter after Y.</i>
W，X，Y
W, X, Y,
Z，Z计划！
Z. PIan Z!
-哦，就在这里，就像你说的 -哦，天哪
<i>- Here it is, just Iike you said. - Oh, boy.</i>
真是邪恶啊
It's eviI.
邪恶极了！
It's diaboIicaI.
这美妙的计划
It's Iemon-scented.
这个Z计划不可能失败！
This PIan Z can't possibIy faiI!
今天就让你好好享受吧，蟹老板
So enjoy today, Mr. Krabs,
因为明天，我就能得到你的秘方
because by tomorrow, I'II have the formuIa.
大家就会来海之霸了
Then everyone wiII eat at the Chum Bucket,
我就能控制全世界！
and I wiII ruIe the worId!
皮老板万岁！皮老板万岁！
AII haiI PIankton. AII haiI PIank--!
我要当经理了 我要当经理了！
I'm ready. Promotion. I'm ready. Promotion.
我是不是踩到什么东西了
I think I stepped in something.
不是什么东西 是我，你这笨蛋
Not in something, on someone, you twit.
对不起，皮老板
Sorry, PIankton.
你是去参加开幕仪式的吗？
Are you on your way to the grand-opening ceremony?
不，我才不是
No, I am not on my way over to the grand-opening ceremony.
我在忙着执行控制全世界的计划！
I'm busy pIanning to ruIe the worId!
哦，那祝你好运
WeII, good Iuck with that.
我要当经理了 我要当经理了
I'm ready. Promotion. I'm ready. Promotion.
笨小孩
Stupid kid.
欢迎，欢迎大家来参加
WeIcome. WeIcome, everyone, to the grand opening
蟹堡王二号的开幕仪式
of The Krusty Krab 2.
-我们付9块钱就是看这个？ -我付了10块呢
- We paid $9 for this? - I paid 1 0.
在我们正式开幕前
Now, before we begin with the ribbon-cutting,
我先来宣布我们的新经理的名字
I'd Iike to announce the name of our new manager.
好！
Yay! Yeah!
好啊！好啊！
Yeah! Now we're taIking! Yeah!
恩，那么
Yes. WeII, anyway...
新的经理是一个忠心的，工作努力的 好员工
The new manager is a IoyaI, hard-working empIoyee.
对
<i>Yes.</i>
是这个工作的当然人选
The obvious choice for the job.
说得对
<i>He's right.</i>
你们都知道的名字，是S开头的
A name you aII know. It starts with an S.
-就是我啊 -请欢迎我们的新经理
<i>- That's me. - PIease weIcome our new manager...</i>
章鱼哥！
...Squidward TentacIes.
好啊！
Yes! Yeah!
祝你下次好运了，章鱼哥！
Oh, better Iuck next time, buddy.
好啊！好啊！
Yeah! AII right!
比奇堡的居民们 作为新的经理
PeopIe of Bikini Bottom, as the manager of--
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob.
大家等等，蟹老板还有个重要消息要宣布
HoId the phone, foIks, I'm getting an important news fIash from Mr. Krabs.
说吧，蟹老板
Go ahead, Mr. K.
我做了一件..什么？
I'm making a compIete what of myseIf?
这是你见过最尴尬的事？
The most embarrassing thing you've ever seen?
而且因为我重复你的话，就更糟糕？
And now it's worse because I'm repeating
在麦克风上扩音所有的话？
everything you say into the microphone?
好吧，说大声点，海绵宝宝 你没得到这个职位
Oh, for crying out Ioud, SpongeBob, you didn't get the job.
-什么？ -你没得到这个职位
- What? - You did not get the job.
但是，为什么？
But-- But why?
海绵宝宝，你是最好的油炸厨师
SpongeBob, you're a great fry cook,
但是我把这个职位给了章鱼哥 因为作为经理
but I gave the job to Squidward because being manager
有重大的责任
is a big responsibiIity.
让我们面对现实吧，他更
WeII, Iet's face it, he's more...
-更成熟一些 -我还不够
- ...mature than you. - I'm not...
成熟？
...mature?
嘿，我想表达的更婉转一些
Lad, I mean this in the nicest of ways,
但是有个词能形容你
but there's a word for what you are,
这个词就是
and that word is...
让我想想
Now, Iet's see...
-笨蛋？ -不，不是，不是笨蛋
- Dork? - No, wait, that's not right. Not a dork.
-毛头小子？ -接近了一些，但是还不是
- A goofbaII? - CIoser, but no, no, no.
-疯子. -小白痴.
- A ding-a-Iing. - Wing nut.
大笨蛋
A KnuckIehead McSpazatron.
好了，够了
Okay, that's enough.
我想说的只是 你还是个孩子
Look, what I'm trying to say is, you're just a kid.
作为经理 你要是个男人才行
And to be a manager, you have to be a man.
不然他们就会叫你小孩经理
Otherwise they'd caII it ''kid-ager.''
你明白吗，小子？ 我是说，你明白吗？
You understand-ager? I mean, you understand?
好吧，蟹老板
I guess so, Mr. Krabs.
海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
我准备好了，沮丧
I'm ready. Depression.
可怜的孩子
Poor kid.
海绵宝宝万岁！
Hooray for SpongeBob!
听听海绵宝宝的演讲吧！
Let's hear it for SpongeBob!
喂？
HeIIo?
大家都到哪儿去了？
Where'd everybody go?
我错过了吗？
Did I miss something?
你们没见到我的屁股吗？
Did you see my butt?
当天深夜
<i>Later that evening...</i>
该执行Z计划了
Time to put PIan Z into effect.
就从海王星国王的水下城堡开始
Starting at the undersea castIe of King Neptune.
哦，对
Oh, right.
皇家法庭现在开庭
The royaI court is now in session.
把囚犯带上来
Bring the prisoner forward.
你已经承认了触摸国王的皇冠 的罪名了是吗？
So you have confessed to the crime of touching the king's crown.
-对，但是 -但是什么？
- Yes, but-- - But what?
但是这是我的工作啊，陛下 我是皇冠缮修师啊
But it's my job, Your Highness. I'm the royaI crown poIisher.
嗯，看来我不能处决你了
WeII, then I guess I can't execute you.
-判你坐20年地牢 -爸爸
- Twenty years in the dungeon it is. - Daddy.
你无罪释放
You're free to go.
愿主赐福给你，公主
BIess you, Princess Mindy.
女儿，你怎敢违抗我
Mindy, how dare you defy me.
你为什么一定要这么苛刻呢？
Why do you have to be so mean?
我是国王，我一定要执行海洋的法令
I am the king. I must enforce the Iaws of the sea.
爸爸，我希望你能试着多 用一点爱和怜悯
Father, I wish you'd try a IittIe Iove and compassion
而不是严酷的惩罚
instead of these harsh punishments.
那就好了
That wouId be nice.
护卫，给我清场
Squire, cIear the room.
我要和我的女儿单独谈谈
I wish to speak to my daughter aIone.
这是什么，女儿？
What is this, Mindy?
-你的皇冠？ -这个皇冠有什么作用呢？
- Your crown? - And what does this crown do?
-藏你的秃头？ -这不是秃头，这只是...
- Covers your baId spot. - It's not baId, it's
稀疏了点
thinning.
这皇冠除了能盖住我已上移的发线外 还有很多作用
This crown does much more than cover a sIightIy receding hairIine.
这个皇冠代表的是统治海洋的身份
No, this crown entitIes the one who wears it to be in charge of the sea.
总有一天，妳也会戴上皇冠
One day, you wiII wear this crown.
我也会秃头？
I'm gonna be baId?
是稀疏！
Thinning!
不管怎么样，我要说的是 直到你学会如何用
Anyway, the point is, you won't wear it
铁腕来统治海洋的时候 妳才能戴上皇冠
untiI you Iearn how to ruIe with an iron fist.
就像妳的父亲
Like your father.
爸爸，你的皇冠
Dad, your ''crown''...
这是？
What the...?
我的皇冠！
My crown!
有人偷了皇冠！
Someone has stoIen the royaI crown!
我拿到了，我拿到了！
I got it. I got it.
嘿，大家，到了该向你们 最喜欢的花生－高菲 高伯
Hey, aII you Goobers, it's time to say howdy
致敬的时候了
to your favourite undersea peanut, Goofy Goober.
你好，高菲 高伯
Howdy, Goofy Goober!
嘿，高菲高伯们 唱歌的时间到了
Hey, feIIow Goofy Goobers. Time to sing.
喔 我是高菲高伯 耶 你是高菲高伯 耶
<i>Oh, l'm a Goofy Goober, yeah You're a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
我们全都是高菲高伯 耶 高菲 高菲高伯 高伯 耶
<i>We're all Goofy Goobers, yeah Goofy, goofy, goober, goober, yeah</i>
好吧，算了，小子
AII right. Get it together, oId boy.
我知道，不要再想它就好了
I know. I'II just stop thinking about it.
嘿，我感觉好多了
Hey, you know, I actuaIIy feeI a IittIe better.
我都不记得我为什么伤心了
I don't even remember why I was sad.
嘿，这不是蟹堡王 二号的经理吗？
Hey, it's the new Krusty Krab 2 manager.
哇，你已经感受到工作的压力了
Wow, the pressure's aIready setting in.
不，派大星，你没明白
No, Pat, you don't understand.
我没升职
I didn't get the promotion.
什么？为什么？
What? Why?
蟹老板认为我是个小孩子
Mr. Krabs thinks I'm a kid.
-什么？这太难以置信了 -我知道
- What? That's insane. - I know.
说你是小孩子，就像是说我是小孩子
WeII, saying you're a kid, it's Iike saying I'm a kid.
-这是您的高伯餐，先生 -不是有附送的玩具吗？
- Here's your Goober MeaI, sir. - I'm supposed to get a toy with this.
谢谢
Thanks.
我要回家了，派大星 庆祝结束了
I'm gonna head home, Pat. The ceIebration's off.
-你确定吗？ -嗯，我心情不好
- Are you sure? - Yeah. I'm not in a Goober mood.
好吧，再见
Okay, see you.
这是您的三层高伯冰淇淋，先生
And here's your TripIe Gooberberry Sunrise, sir.
三层高伯冰淇淋？
TripIe Gooberberry Sunrise, huh?
我想我可以吃一点再走
I guess I couId use one of those.
哈哈，好啊
Now you're taIking.
嘿，侍者，我们还要一个
Hey, waiter, we need another one over here.
来了
There you go.
哈，来得正好
Boy, Pat, that hit the spot.
-我现在感觉好多了 -好啊
- I'm feeIing better aIready. - Yeah.
侍者，再来一轮
Waiter, Iet's get another round over here.
-亲爱的侍者先生，再来两个
Oh, Mr. Waiter. Two more, pIease.
侍者先生
Waiter.
Oh, waiter.
侍者先生
Waiter.
-侍者先生！ -为什么我总是要伺候这些笨蛋？
- Waiter! - Why do I aIways get the nuts?
大家好，我要送给我最好的两个朋友
AII right, foIks, this one goes out to my two bestest friends
派大星和这个大花生
in the whoIe worId:
Patrick and this big peanut guy.
我们团名是
It's a IittIe ditty caIIed...
侍者先生！
...''Waiter!''
嘿，起来
Hey. Hey, get up.
起来，孩子，我要回家了
Hey, come on, buddy. I wanna go home.
来啊，孩子
Come on, paI.
哦，我头疼
Oh, my head.
听着，早上8点了
Listen to me. It's 8 in the morning.
把你朋友叫起来，走吧
Go scrape up your friend and get going.
我朋友
My friend?
派大星，嘿，你怎么样了？
Patrick. Hey, what's up, buddy?
等等，你说8点了
Wait, you said 8:00.
我上班要迟到了 蟹老板会这样
I'm Iate for work. Mr. Krabs is gonna be...
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs.
听着，章鱼哥
Now, pay attention, Squidward.
作为新的经理，你要密切注意 新来的客人
As new manager, you've gotta keep a sharp eye out for paying customers.
嗯
Yawn.
这是谁？海王星国王午餐时间到了吗
What's this? King Neptune is riding toward The Krusty Krab at Iunchtime.
他可有钱了
He's got money.
坐着等我，女儿 我马上回来
Stay in the coach, daughter. This won't take Iong.
爸爸，我觉得您反应太偏激了
Daddy, pIease. I think you're overreacting.
住嘴，公主 我知道我在干什么
SiIence, Mindy. I know what I'm doing.
-卫兵 -是，陛下
- Squire. - Yes, Your Highness.
马上给我把这根柱子处决掉
Have this poIe executed at once.
美味蟹堡要101块钱？
A hundred and one doIIars for a Krabby Patty?
是加起司的，章鱼哥 加起司的
With cheese, Mr. Squidward, with cheese.
你们好啊
Greeting, subjects.
我在找一个叫做蟹老板的人
I seek the one known as Eugene Krabs.
叫他立即来见我
May he present himseIf to me at once.
我就是蟹老板，陛下 您要点什么吃的吗？
I'm Eugene Krabs, Your Highness. WouId you Iike to order something?
不，我要的是你！蟹老板！
Nay! I'm on to you, Krabs!
你偷了我的皇冠，你无法抵赖
You have stoIen the royaI crown, you cannot deny.
虽然你很聪明
For, cIever as you are,
不过还是在现场漏了一样 重要的证据
you Ieft one damning piece of evidence at the scene of the crime.
我偷了你的皇冠 蟹老板签名
''I stoIe your crown. Signed, Eugene Krabs.''
马上把皇冠还给我
ReIinquish the royaI crown to me at once.
但是，我没偷啊
But-- But this is crazy. I didn't do it.
这里是蟹老板，请留言
<i>Ahoy, this is Eugene Krabs. Leave a message.</i>
嘿，蟹老板，是克雷 买你的海王星皇冠的人
<i>Hi, Mr. Krabs. This is Clay, the guy you sold Neptune's crown to.</i>
我只是想再次感谢你卖给我皇冠
<i>Yeah, l just wanted to say thanks again for selling me the crown.</i>
海王星的皇冠 我把它卖给了贝壳城的一个人
<i>Neptune's crown. l sold it to a guy in Shell City,</i>
我想再次感谢你卖给我皇冠
<i>and l just wanted to say thanks again for selling me the crown.</i>
海王星的皇冠
<i>Neptune's crown.</i>
现在在贝壳城了，再见
<i>Which is now in Shell City. Goodbye.</i>
打错电话总是很烦人的不是吗？
Don't you just hate wrong numbers?
我的皇冠在禁区，贝壳城？
My crown is in the forbidden SheII City?!
Z计划，我爱Z计划
PIan Z. I Iove PIan Z.
死吧，蟹老板
Prepare to burn, Krabs.
等等，海王星 求你了
Wait, Neptune. PIease, I'm begging you.
我不是个骗子 你可以问任何人，他们可以向你保证
I ain't a crook. Ask anyone, they'II vouch for me.
好吧，那么
Very weII, then.
在我把这个甲壳骗子烧熟之前
Before I turn this conniving crustacean into fishmeaI,
你们有谁要替蟹老板说句话的吗？
who here has anything to say about Eugene Krabs?
我有话要说
I've got something to say about Mr. Krabs.
海绵宝宝，你来得正好
SpongeBob, me boy, you've come just in time.
-对不起 -请告诉海王星国王
- Pardon me, miss. - PIease, teII King Neptune
关于我的一切
aII about me.
我为蟹老板工作好多年了
I have worked for Mr. Krabs for many years
一向认为他是个很好的老板
and aIways thought he was a great boss.
你看到吗？很好的老板
You see? A great boss.
我现在认识到，他是个大骗子！
I now reaIize that he's a great big jerk!
我应该得到那个经理的职位！
I deserve that manager's job!
但是你没有给我，因为你说我是个小孩子
But you didn't give it to me, because you say I'm a kid.
我是个100％的男人！
WeII, I am 1 00-percent man!
这个男人有话要说
And this man has got something to say to you.
嗯，我想我讲完了
There. I think I made my point.
还有别人吗？
Anyone eIse?
没有了？好的
No? WeII, then.
我裤子着火了！
Me pants are on fire!
我内裤着火了！
Me underwear's on fire!
我着火了！
I'm on fire!
哦
Oh, yeah.
现在，蟹老板，你将会被
And now, Eugene Krabs, you wiII--
等等
Wait.
我很感谢你为我做这些
I'm fIattered you wouId do this on my account,
但没当成经理还不至于要杀了他啊
but being manager isn't worth kiIIing Mr. Krabs over.
闭嘴，笨蛋，蟹老板偷了我的皇冠 现在皇冠在贝壳城
Quiet, fooI! Mr. Krabs stoIe my crown, and now it's in SheII City.
-所以他必须死 -这是不是太严酷了
- That's why he must die. - Doesn't it seem a IittIe harsh
为了皇冠就要杀人？
to kiII someone over a crown?
你不懂的，我的皇冠代表了 我至高无上的权力
You don't understand. My crown is a symboI of my king-Iike authority.
在你和我之间
And between you and me...
我的头发有点稀疏
...my hair is thinning a bit.
哦，陛下，我确定 还不是那么引人注意的
Oh, Your Highness, I'm sure it's not that notice-- BaId. BaId.
-秃头！秃头！ -秃头！秃头！
- BaId! BaId! - BaId! BaId!
我的眼睛！
My eyes!
好了，好了
AII right, aII right.
海王星国王陛下？
King Neptune, sir?
如果我去把您的皇冠拿回来 您就能赦免蟹老板吗？
WouId you spare Mr. Krabs' Iife if I went to get your crown back?
你，去贝壳城？
You, go to SheII City?
没人能从贝壳城活着回来
No one who's gone to SheII City has ever returned.
你凭什么认为你行？ 你只是个小孩子
What makes you think you couId? You're just a kid.
我不是个小孩子，我做的到
But I'm not a kid. I can do it.
走开，我要烧死这头蟹
Run aIong, I have a crab to cook.
不，我不会答应
No! I won't Iet you.
好吧
Very weII, then.
那我就烧掉你们两个
I'II have to fry you both.
爸爸，不要
Daddy, stop it.
你一天不杀人就不舒服吗？
Can't you get through one day without executing someone?
公主，我告诉你在马车里等着
Mindy. I toId you to stay in the carriage.
你的爱和怜悯到哪里去了？
Where's your Iove and compassion?
看看这个小家伙
Look at this IittIe guy.
他愿意冒生命危险去找到皇冠 救他的老板
He's wiIIing to risk his Iife to find your crown and save his boss.
-但是，女儿，我 -求你了，爸爸
- But, daughter, I-- - PIease, Father?
让他试试看 你又没什么损失
At Ieast Iet him try. What have you got to Iose?
需要我提醒你一下 你的私密问题吗？
Might I remind you of your speciaI probIem?
-秃头，秃头！ -秃头！
- BaId! BaId! BaId! - BaId!
-秃头！ -我的眼睛！
- BaId! BaId! - My eyes!
好吧
AII right.
好吧，公主
Very weII, Mindy.
我给他个机会
I'II give him a chance.
但是如果你的小家伙回不来
But when your IittIe champion faiIs to return,
我就把这头蟹烧个唏哩哗啦
I get to spIatter this crab aII over the waIIs.
至于你，你要10天之内把我的皇冠 带回来
And as for you, be back here with my crown in exactIy ten days.
-他9天就行 -8天
- He can do it in nine. - Eight.
- Seven. - Six.
-派大星！ -派大星！
- Patrick! - Patrick!
那就六天吧
Six it is, then.
-5天 -派大星，住嘴
- Five. - Patrick, shush.
在那之前，螃蟹要被冻起来
UntiI then, the crab shaII remain frozen where he now stands.
不，等等，求你了
No, wait. I'm begging you.
谁把空调打开了？蟹老板？
Who turned on the AC? Mr. Krabs!
哦，这太可怕了
Oh, no, this is terribIe.
谁来给我发工资啊？
Who's gonna sign my paycheck?
走吧，公主
Come aIong, Mindy.
听着，通往贝壳城的道路非常危险
Listen, you guys, the road to SheII City is reaIIy dangerous.
那里有骗子，杀手，到处都是怪兽
There's crooks, kiIIers and monsters everywhere.
还有更坏的 有个独眼巨人
And what's worse, there's a giant CycIops
霸占通往城市的道路，还会 捕捉无辜的海洋生物
who guards the outskirts of the city and preys on innocent sea creatures.
不要让他抓到你 如果他抓到你的话
Don't Iet him catch you, because if he does,
他会把你带回他的巢穴 你就不能活着回来了
he'II take you back to his Iair, and you'II never be seen again.
她真漂亮，海绵宝宝
She's purty, SpongeBob.
拿着这个
Here, take this.
这里面是什么？
What's in here?
这是一袋魔法风
It's a magicaI bag of winds.
-我从爸爸那里偷来的 -你真漂亮
- I stoIe them from my father. - You're hot.
你一找到皇冠，就打开这个袋子
Once you find the crown, open the bag of winds
你就会被吹回家来
and you'II be bIown back home.
-公主！ -来了！
- Mindy! - I'm coming.
-祝你好运，海绵宝宝 -等等，你怎么知道我的名字？
- Good Iuck, SpongeBob. - Wait. How did you know my name?
哦，有一天我会成为海中的女王
Oh, I'm gonna be queen of the sea one day.
我学过所有海洋生物的名字
I've Iearned the names of aII the sea creatures.
我的名字呢？
What's my name?
这个容易，你是派大星
That's easy. You're Patrick Star.
-公主！ -我走了，我相信你们！
- Mindy! - I gotta go. I beIieve in you guys.
谢谢，公主
Thanks, Mindy.
不用担心，蟹老板 派大星，章鱼哥和我
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs. Patrick, Squidward and I--
算了
Pass.
-派大星和我 -嘿
- Patrick and I... - Hi.
我们会拿到那个皇冠， 把你从海王星那里救回来
...are gonna get that crown back and save you from Neptune's wrath.
你不用担心，我们会救你的
You've got nothing to worry about. Your Iife is in our hands.
派大星，我们去拿回皇冠
Patrick, Iet's go get that crown.
-大饱眼福吧，派大星 -这是什么？
- Feast your eyes, Patrick. - What is it?
蟹堡飞车
The Patty Wagon.
是蟹老板在促销的时候用的
Mr. Krabs uses it for promotionaI reasons.
让你看看它的一些特性吧
Let me show you some of its features.
点缀芝麻的外壳 铁束带的泡菜轮子
Sesame-seed finish, steeI-beIted pickIes,
烤肉的皮座椅 至于发动机
griIIed-Ieather interior. And under the hood,
电喷式的炸薯条机， 带双头的油脂分离器
a fueI-injected french-fryer with duaI overhead grease traps.
-哇 -是啊，哇
- Wow. - Yeah, wow.
嘿，我记得你没有驾照
Hey, I thought you didn't have a driver's Iicense.
驾驶三明治不需要驾照
You don't need a Iicense to drive a sandwich.
-贝壳城我们来了！ -贝壳城我们来了！
- SheII City, here we come! - SheII City, here we come!
笨蛋
Ding-a-Iing.
嘿，老朋友，不许动
Hey there, oId buddy. Freeze.
我要一份蟹堡秘方，带走的，谢谢
One secret formuIa to go, pIease.
哦，不用麻烦你了，我自己拿
No, no, don't troubIe yourseIf. I'II get it.
我很愿意多留一会， 不过我还要去做美味蟹堡
WeII, I'd Iike to hang around, but I've got Krabby Patties to make...
在我的海之霸餐厅
...over at the Chum Bucket.
Z计划，我爱你
PIan Z, I Iove you.
<i>Oh, l'm a Goofy Goober, yeah You're a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
<i>We're all Goofy Goobers, yeah Goofy, goofy, goober, goober, yeah</i>
请加满油，谢谢
FiII her up, pIease.
加芥末还是西红柿酱？
What'II it be, feIIas, mustard or ketchup?
他们在笑我们吗？
Are they Iaughing at us?
不，派大星 他们在笑我们旁边的
No, Patrick, they're Iaughing next to us.
你们两个笨小孩去哪里？
Where you two dumb kids headed, anyway?
-小孩？ -不，派大星
- Kids? - Now, Patrick.
告诉你 我们不是小孩，我们是男人
For your information, we are not kids, we are men.
我们要去贝壳城 把海王星国王的皇冠拿回来
And we're off to get King Neptune's crown in SheII City.
-贝壳城？ -贝壳城？
- SheII City? - SheII City?
就是独眼巨人在的地方？
Ain't that the pIace that's guarded by a kiIIer CycIops?
对
That's right.
罗德，脱帽致敬啊
LIoyd, take off your hat in respect.
向死人致敬！
Respect for the dead!
你们两个笨蛋 过了分界线连10秒都办不到
You two dipsticks ain't gonna Iast ten seconds over the county Iine.
是吗？让我们试试看啊
Oh, yeah? We'II see about that.
下车，朋友们
Out of the car, feIIas.
那有多少秒？
How many seconds was that?
12秒
TweIve.
-怎么样？ -哈哈
- In your face. - In your face.
我怎么说的，哈哈
That's what I'm taIking about. Yeah.
现在谁是小孩子？
Who's the kid now?
他们死定了
They're dead.
现在播报一个难以置信的 新闻
Perch Perkins here with an incredibIe news fIash.
皮老板在出售美味蟹堡 在海之霸餐厅
PIankton is seIIing Krabby Patties at the Chum Bucket.
这怎么可能？我们来看看
How is this possibIe? Let's find out.
请排好队，人人都买的到
Step right up. PIenty for everybody.
对不起，皮老板 我们比奇堡新闻台
<i>Excuse me, PIankton. Perch Perkins, Bikini Bottom News.</i>
-我能占用你1分钟吗？ -没问题，这是我的荣幸
- Can I get a minute? - Anything for you, Perch.
比奇堡的人都想知道 你怎么做的出美味蟹堡呢？
AII of Bikini Bottom wants to know, how did you get the Krabby Patty?
在我的最好的朋友 蟹老板
WeII, Perch, before my dear friend Eugene Krabs
被海王星国王冰冻起来之前
was frozen by King Neptune...
对不起
I'm sorry.
他委托给我一项秘密的任务
He confided in me a secret wish.
在我不在的时候，请在海之霸卖美味蟹堡 他是这么说的
''SeII the Krabby Patty in my absence at the Chum Bucket,'' he said.
不要让美味蟹堡失传！
''Don't Iet the fIame die out.''
另外，现在购买一个美味蟹堡 就能免费获得海之霸头盔
By the way, act now and you get a free Chum Bucket bucket heImet
拿着
with every purchase. Here you go, Perch.
-谢谢 -每人都能获得海之霸头盔！
- Thanks. - Bucket heImets for everyone!
我的头盔！
My heImet!
宝贝， 自从你答应我的求婚以来
Karen, baby, I haven't feIt this giddy
我从来没感到过这样的狂喜
since the day you agreed to be my wife.
我从来没答应过
<i>l never agreed.</i>
邪恶的Z计划完美实施
EviI PIan Z is working perfectIy.
现在没有什么能阻止我了
Nothing can stop me now.
除了海绵宝宝和他的粉红朋友之外
<i>Nothing except SpongeBob and his pink friend.</i>
我的探测器告诉我他们在找皇冠
<i>My sensors indicate that they're going after the crown.</i>
如果他们成功归来， 海王星就能找到一些指纹
<i>lf they make it back, Neptune might discover some fingerprints.</i>
细小的指纹
<i>Tiny fingerprints.</i>
又短又细小的指纹
<i>Stubby, tiny fingerprints.</i>
邪恶计划Z比你高明，宝贝
EviI PIan Z is way ahead of you, baby.
我已经雇了人去解决那两个了
I've aIready hired someone to take care of those two.
他是个邪恶的，冷血的杀手
He's a vicious, coId-bIooded predator.
芝麻种子..
Sesame seed.
嘿，先生
Hey, mister.
那个帽子能装的下10加仑吗？
Does that hat take ten gaIIons?
-继续走 -嗯，嗯
- Going on. - Yeah. Yeah.
-继续 -继续走
- Moving on. - Just keep going.
对
Yup.
要拿到皇冠
Gonna get that crown.
哦，对
Oh, yeah.
-好的 -好的
- AII right. - AII right.
胜利
Yeah. Victory.
-到了吗？ -一定已经很近了
- Are we there yet? - We must be cIose by now.
派大星，看，我们干得好！
Patrick, Iook. We're doing great!
离贝壳城还有5天路程
SheII City's onIy five days away.
开车的话
By car.
我希望我们还有车
I wish we stiII had our car.
海绵宝宝，看啊
SpongeBob, Iook.
我们的车！
Our car!
-钥匙 -你觉得会在哪儿？
- The key. - Where do you think it is?
就在那儿，派大星，钥匙！
There it is, Pat. The key!
现在，怎么拿到钥匙呢？
Now, how are we gonna get it?
我知道，进去问他要就行了
I know. WaIk in and ask him for it.
你看什么？
What are you Iooking at?
-派大星，这个主意笨死了 -对不起
- Patrick, that's a terribIe idea. - Sorry.
我知道了，我进去，引开他们注意力 然后你拿钥匙
I know. I'II go in and create a distraction, and you get the key.
等等，我去引开注意力
Wait. I wanna do the distraction.
好吧，我觉得谁引开注意力也没多大区别
Okay. I guess it reaIIy doesn't matter who does the distraction.
You see me waIking back--?
大家注意！
Can I have everybody's attention?
我要上厕所
I have to use the bathroom.
就在那边
It's right over there.
我的隐形眼镜呢？哦，在这里 我要拿去洗洗
Stupid contacts. Oh, there it is. I better go wash it off.
派大星，你把那个叫做引开注意力？
Patrick. You caII that a distraction?
嗯，我是要上厕所啊
WeII, I had to go to the bathroom.
我白把手弄脏了
WeII, I got my hands dirty for nothing.
派大星，看看！
Patrick, check it out.
-万岁！ -万岁！
- Hooray! - Hooray!
-泡泡派对！ -泡泡派对！
- BubbIe party! - BubbIe party!
嘿！
Hey!
谁吹的泡泡？
Who bIew this bubbIe?
你们都知道规矩吧？
You aII know the ruIes!
任何吹泡泡的家伙将会被 所有酒吧里的顾客
AII bubbIe-bIowing babies wiII be beaten senseIess
一起揍个半死
by every abIe-bodied patron in the bar.
对，那么是谁吹的泡泡？
That's right! So who bIew it?
没人知道？
So nobody knows.
-也许是 -闭嘴！
- Maybe it was-- - Shut up!
这里有人不说老实话
Somebody in here ain't a reaI man.
你们听着！我们要找人！
You! We're on a baby hunt.
不要以为我没办法把你揪出来
And don't think we don't know how to weed them out.
站成一排！
Now, everybody Iine up.
DJ，测试时间到了
DJ, time for the test.
无人能抗拒，不跟着这一起唱
No baby can resist singing aIong to this.
海绵宝宝，是高菲 高伯主题歌
SpongeBob, it's the Goofy Goober theme song.
我知道
I know.
<i>Oh, l'm a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
<i>You're a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
<i>We're all Goofy Goobers, yeah Goofy, goofy, goober, goober, yeah</i>
-是你，你就是！ -不，我只是咳嗽，我发誓！
- It was you! You're the baby! - No, no! I onIy coughed, I swear.
DJ！声音放大些！
DJ ! Turn it up Iouder!
不要一起唱，派大星
Don't sing aIong, Patrick.
我在努力
I'm trying.
尽量努力
Trying so hard.
<i>l'm a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
<i>You're a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
<i>We're all Goofy Goobers, yeah</i>
<i>Goofy, goofy, goober, goobers, yeah</i>
好吧
WeII, weII, weII.
是你们？
Which one of you babies was it?
-是他 -是他
- It was him. - It was him.
- He did it. - He did it.
我从来没去那里吃过
I've never even eaten at--
<i>Goofy, goofy, goober, goobers, yeah</i>
好啊，看来我们已经找到那个家伙了
WeII, Iooks Iike we got ourseIves a doubIe baby.
啊，好险啊
Man, that was a cIose caII.
看看我找到什么了
Guess what I got.
钥匙！
The key!
好耶， 终于可以享受海绵宝宝不在的时光了
Too bad SpongeBob's not here to enjoy SpongeBob not being here.
早上好
Morning.
有些人戴帽子的品味真差
Some peopIe have no taste in headgear.
还有婴儿也戴？
Babies too?
对不起，小姐
Excuse me, miss,
大家都戴的这种丑陋的帽子 是从哪儿来的？
but where is everybody getting that horrid headwear?
谁说的？
Who said that?
在下面
Down here.
我在海之霸拿到的
WeII, I got it at the Chum Bucket.
买美味蟹堡，皮老板就 免费送这头盔
PIankton's giving them away free with every Krabby Patty.
海之霸？免费？美味蟹堡？
Chum Bucket? Free? Krabby Patty?
皮老板？附送？
PIankton? Giving? With?
你在卖美味蟹堡吗？皮老板？
So you're seIIing Krabby Patties, PIankton?
对，章鱼哥
That's right, Squidward.
而且每买一个 还送免费的海之霸头盔
And there's a free bucket heImet with every purchase.
想要一个吗？
Care for one?
不，你也许能骗过比奇堡的所有人
No. You may have hoodwinked everyone eIse in this backwater town,
但是休想骗过我
but you can't fooI me.
我听广播的
I Iisten to pubIic radio.
-那是什么意思？ -意思就是你设计陷害蟹老板
- And what's that supposed to mean? - It means you set up Mr. Krabs.
你偷了皇冠，海王星就把他 冻起来了
You stoIe the crown so Neptune wouId freeze him
你就能用你的小短爪子偷到 美味蟹堡的秘方
and you couId finaIIy get your stubby IittIe paws on the Krabby Patty formuIa.
完全是你一个人
It was you aII aIong.
但是你犯了个致命的错误
But you made one fataI mistake.
你让我拿不到工资
You messed with my paycheck.
我要把你的行为报告给 最高长官
And I'm gonna report you to the highest authority in the Iand,
海王星国王
King Neptune!
那我们走着瞧吧 大嘴检察官
We'II see about that, Inspector LooseIips.
启动大脑控制程序
<i>Now activating helmet brain-control devices.</i>
什么？
What?
皮老板万岁
<i>All hail Plankton.</i>
-怎么了？ -皮老板万岁
<i>- What's going on here? - All hail Plankton.</i>
抓住他，奴隶们
Seize him, sIaves!
皮老板万岁
<i>All hail Plankton.</i>
我要赶快走
I'm getting out of here!
皮老板万岁
<i>All hail Plankton.</i>
谁能阻止我？
Who can stop me now?
谁？
Who?
-来啊，派大星，再来一次 -好吧
- Come on, Pat, one more time. - Okay.
我们要找一个人，不要以为我 不知道怎么把你揪出来
We're on a baby hunt. And don't think we don't know how to weed them out.
把你揪出来
''Weed them out.''
笨蛋
What a jerk.
这里的路有点颠簸啊
The road's getting kind of bumpy here.
你知道，海绵宝宝
You know, SpongeBob,
从这里可以学到一个经验
there's a Iesson to be Iearned from aII of this.
是什么？
What's that, Patrick?
吹泡泡的家伙不属于这里
A bubbIe-bIowing doubIe baby doesn't beIong out here
在男人的小国家里
in man's country.
嗯，等等
Yeah. Wait.
我们吹的泡泡
We bIew that bubbIe.
那不就是说我们是吹泡泡 的家伙？
Doesn't that make us a bubbIe-bIowing doubIe baby?
嘿，看啊，免费的冰淇淋！
Hey, Iook, free ice cream!
哦，太好了
Oh, boy!
你好啊
How you doing?
等等
Wait a minute.
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob!
嗯？
Yeah?
给我要个有巧克力的！
Make mine a chocoIate!
知道了，要两个
Got you covered. Two, pIease.
没问题
CertainIy.
好好享受
You kids enjoy.
我们是男人，女士，不过谢谢了
ActuaIIy, we're men, Iady, but thanks.
好，派大星，我们
Okay, Patrick, Iet's...
你可以放手了，我说请放手
You can Iet go now. I said, Iet go, pIease.
这是什么？
What is this?
你是什么老太婆啊？
What kind of oId Iady are you?
你拿到冰淇淋了吗？
Did you get the ice cream?
踩油门啊，派大星！
Step on it, Patrick!
嘿！
Hey!
你也许不知道，牛仔
You may not know it, cowboy,
但是关于吹泡泡，我们这里有规定的
but we got a ruIe around here about bIowing bubbIes.
任何吹泡泡的人 都会被揍个半死
AII bubbIe-bIowing babies wiII be beaten senseIess by every
被
abIe-bodied...
-揍个半死
- In bar... - Bar...
来啊，孩子们，吃点冰淇淋
Come on, kiddies, have some ice cream.
我可以让你们摸摸维斯克斯
I'II Iet you pet Mr. Whiskers.
快跳，派大星！
Jump for it, Patrick!
我们又没有车了
WeII, we Iost our car again.
不管车了，路在哪儿？
Never mind the car, where's the road?
路，路，路
Road. Road. Road.
路，路
路，对不起
Road. R-- Sorry.
路在那儿
There's the road.
在另外一边，过了这个
On the other side of this...
深的，黑的
...deep, dark...
危险的
...dangerous...
有害的
- Hazardous. - ...hazardous...
怪兽盘踞的
Monster-infested.
对，怪兽盘踞的
Yeah, monster-infested...
深渊
...trench.
嘿，海绵宝宝，看啊
Hey, SpongeBob, Iook!
有条路下去
Here's the way down.
光站在这里是拿不到皇冠的
WeII, we're not gonna get the crown standing here.
去贝壳城吧
On to SheII City.
嘿，有声音啊
Hey, Iook, it's making noise.
海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
-你去哪儿？ -我回家了，派大星
- Hey, where are you going? - I'm going home, Patrick.
蟹老板怎么办？
But what about Mr. Krabs?
我们怎么办？
What about us?
我们不可能活着走出深渊的
We'II never survive in that trench!
你自己说的，这是男人的国家
You said it yourseIf, this is man's country.
面对现实吧，派大星，我们只是
And Iet's face it, Pat. We're just...
-小孩子 -我们不是孩子
- ...kids. - We're not kids.
看看吧，派大星
Open your eyes, Patrick!
我们吹泡泡，我们吃冰淇淋
We bIow bubbIes, we eat ice cream.
我们崇拜一个跳舞的花生！
We worship a dancing peanut, for corn's sake!
我们不属于这里！
We don't beIong out here!
我们不是崇拜他
We do not worship him.
你穿这条高菲 高伯花生派对的内裤
You've been wearing the same Goofy Goober Peanut Party underpants
已经穿了三年了
for three years straight.
你这还不是崇拜？
What do you caII that?
崇拜？
Worship?
你是对的，海绵宝宝，我们是小孩
You're right, SpongeBob. We are kids.
把你的裤子穿好，派大星
PuII your pants up, Patrick.
-我们回家吧 -但是你们不能回家去！
- We're going home. - But you can't go home.
公主！
Mindy!
公主？
Mindy?
-你听到了多少？ -足够多了
- How much did you hear? - I heard enough.
-你看到我的内裤了吗？ -没有，派大星
- Did you see my underwear? - No, Patrick.
你想看吗？
Did you want to?
你们也许是小孩子
Look, guys, you may be kids,
但你们 是唯一能拿回皇冠的人了
but you're the onIy ones Ieft who can get that crown.
你说唯一，什么意思？
What do you mean, the onIy ones Ieft?
自从你们离开比奇堡 事情变得很严重了
Things have gotten a Iot worse since you Ieft Bikini Bottom.
皮老板统治了一切
Or shouId I say PIanktopoIis.
皮老板万岁
<i>All hail Plankton.</i>
不许休息！
No resting!
这座我的纪念碑不可能自己建造好的
This monument ceIebrating my gIory isn't gonna buiId itseIf.
动作快点！
Move faster!
哦，看啊，派大星
Oh, my gosh! Patrick, Iook!
皮老板把所有人都变成了奴隶
PIankton's turned everyone we know into sIaves.
章鱼哥
Squidward.
珊迪
Sandy.
泡芙阿姨
Mrs. Puff.
甚至小蜗
Even Gary.
皮老板
PIankton.
你爸爸不能作什么吗？
Can't your father do something?
爸爸在忙着治他的秃头呢
My father's too distracted by his baId spot to do anything.
卫兵，快点
Squire, wiII you hurry.
你们看，你们不能放弃
So you see, you can't quit.
比奇堡的未来就在你们手中
The fate of Bikini Bottom rests in your hands.
-但是，但是我们只是 -就算你们是小孩也没关系
- But-- But we're just-- - Hey. It doesn't matter if you're kids.
是小孩有怎么样？小孩能办大事呢！
And what's so wrong with being a kid, anyway? Kids ruIe!
要办这件事也不一定要是男人啊
You don't need to be a man to do this.
你要相信你们自己
You just gotta beIieve in yourseIf.
你要相信
You just gotta beIieve!
-我相信 -就是这种精神
- I beIieve. - That's the spirit.
我相信
I beIieve that
我认识的所有人都失去灵魂了！
everybody I know is a goner!
来啊，你们
Come on, guys.
嘿
Guys.
嘿？
Guys?
哦
Oh, boy.
想想，公主
Think, Mindy, think.
对，我想你们是对的
Yup, I guess you're right.
两个小孩是不能成功完成任务的
A coupIe of kids couId never survive this journey.
所以 我要把你们变成真正的男人
That's why I guess I'II just have to turn you into men.
你能做的到吗？怎么做？
You can do that? How?
用我的美人鱼魔法
With my mermaid magic.
你听见了吗？派大星？
Did you hear that, Patrick?
她要用她的美人鱼魔法 把我们变成男人！
She'II use her mermaid magic to turn us into men!
万岁！
Hooray!
我们变成男人！ 我们变成男人！
We're gonna be men! We're gonna be men! We're gonna be men!
好，开始吧
Good. Now, Iet's get started.
闭上眼睛
CIose your eyes.
-我们变成男人了吗？ -还没有
- Are we men yet? - Not yet.
转三圈
Spin around three times.
我觉得有用啊
I think it's working.
好的，继续闭着眼睛
Good. Now, keep your eyes shut.
我用美人鱼魔法
With my mermaid's magic
用我的一个尾鳍
and my one taiIfin,
我命令你们两个变成男人！
I command the two of you to turn into men!
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes.
我没感觉到，哦，上帝 派大星，你长胡子了
I don't feeI any-- Oh, my gosh, Patrick, you have a moustache!
你也是！
So do you!
现在你们是男人了 你们能到贝壳城去吗？
So now that you're men, can you make it to SheII City?
-嘿 -嗯？
- Guys. - Yeah?
我说，你们现在是男人了 你们能去贝壳城吗？
I said, now that you're men, can you make it to SheII City?
当然了！
Heck, yeah!
-男人惧怕任何东西吗？ -当然不了！
- Are men afraid of anything? - Heck, no!
为什么？
And why?
因为我们是无敌的！
Because we're invincibIe!
-好啊！ -好啊！
- Yeah! - Yeah!
我从没这么说过
I never said that.
-好啊！ -好啊！
- Yeah! - Yeah!
-好啊！
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah.
-派大星？ -嗯？
- Patrick? - Yeah, buddy?
为什么我们要跳下来而不是 爬梯子？
Why did we jump over the edge instead of taking the stairs?
因为
Bec--
嗯
WeII...
-派大星 -我们死了吗？
- Patrick. - Are we dead?
不，还早着呢，朋友
No. Far from it, my friend.
我们安全到达深渊底部
We're safe and sound at the bottom of this trench.
胡子真的有作用！
The moustaches worked!
你知道这是什么意思吗？
Do you know what that means?
我们真的是无敌的！
We are invincibIe!
现在我们是男子汉 我们什么都能做
<i>Now that we're men We can do anything</i>
现在我们是男子汉 我们是无敌的
<i>Now that we're men We are invincible</i>
现在我们是男子汉 我们将要去贝壳城
<i>Now that we're men We'll go to Shell City</i>
拿回王冠，拯救城镇 还有蟹老板
<i>Get the crown, save the town And Mr. Krabs</i>
现在我们是男子汉
<i>Now that we're men</i>
我们脸上有胡子
<i>We have facial hair</i>
现在我们是男子汉
<i>Now that we're men</i>
我换了我的内裤
<i>l change my underwear</i>
现在我们是男子汉 我们有男子汉的天赋
<i>Now that we're men We've got a manly flair</i>
我们有男子汉的素质 我们够气魄去拯救世界
<i>We've got the stuff We're tough enough to save the day</i>
当我们是孩子时 绝没有这机会
<i>We never had a chance when we were kids</i>
没! 没! 没!
<i>No! No! No!</i>
但是看看美人鱼所做的这一切
<i>But take a look at what the mermaid did</i>
对，就是这样，派大星
Yeah, go, Pat.
对
Oh, yeah.
对，就是这样，海绵宝宝
Yeah, go, SpongeBob.
万岁！
Hooray!
<i>Now that they're men We can't bother them</i>
<i>Now that they're men They have become our friends</i>
<i>Now that they're men There'll be a happy end</i>
<i>They'll pass the test And finish the quest for the crown</i>
<i>They'll pass the test</i>
<i>And finish the quest</i>
<i>They'll pass the test And finish the quest for the crown</i>
贝壳城，往前走
''SheII City, dead ahead.''
我们成功了，派大星
We did it, Pat!
我们经历了各种艰难
We made it past everything!
甚至丑陋恶心的怪兽
Even the hideous, disgusting monsters.
不是说你们
Not you guys.
你们是好人！
You guys are awesome!
好的，派大星，我们马上就到了
WeII, Patrick, we shouId be there in one more verse.
-我们是男人 -终于
<i>- Now that we're men-- - FinaIIy.</i>
我找到你们了
I got you right where I want you.
我能帮你什么忙吗，先生？
Can I heIp you with something, sir?
我叫丹尼斯
Name's Dennis.
我被雇佣来终结你们
I've been hired to exterminate you.
你来终结我们？
You're gonna exterminate us?
听着，小子
Listen, junior,
我和我朋友今天心情不错
you caught me and my friend here in a good mood today,
所以我只给你一个忠告
so I'm gonna Iet you off with a warning.
站开一点，就不用受到 我们胡须的愤怒所发出的惩罚了
Step aside, and you won't have to feeI
the awesome wrath of our moustaches.
你说这些吗？
You mean these?
我还以为你们午餐的 菜渣卡在脸上呢
I thought you stiII had a piece of saIad stuck to your Iip from Iunchtime.
是假的胡子？
They were fake?
当然是假的！
Of course they were fake!
真的胡须是这样的！
This is what a reaI moustache Iooks Iike.
-他是美人鱼吗？ -好了，闲话说够了
- Is he a mermaid? - AII right. Enough gab.
他会干什么？
What are you gonna do to us?
皮老板说的很清楚
PIankton was very specific.
皮老板？
PIankton?
由于某些原因，他要我踩死你们
For some reason, he wanted me to step on you.
踩死我们？
Step on us?
对，那样你们永远也不会发现 是他偷了皇冠！
Yeah! That way you'II never find out that he stoIe the crown!
也许我说的太多了
Perhaps I've said too much.
他的靴子真大！
That's a big boot.
不要担心
Don't worry.
会很疼的
This wiII onIy hurt a Iot.
我喜欢这个工作！
I Iove this job!
-更大的脚！ -等等，派大星
- Bigger boot! - Wait, Pat.
这只更大的脚救了我们
This bigger boot saved our Iives.
谢谢你，陌生人
Thank you, stranger.
陌生人？
Stranger?
是独眼巨人！
It's the CycIops!
救命啊！
HeIp us! HeIp us!
Save us, someone!
我们死了吗？
Are we dead?
我觉得没有
I don't think so.
人工上色的石头？
ArtificiaIIy coIoured rocks?
我不知道我们在哪儿
I don't know where we are.
这是什么？
What is this?
是精神力量造出来的墙
It's some kind of waII of psychic energy.
不，派大星，是个巨大的玻璃缸！
No, Pat, it's a giant gIass bowI.
嘿，那里有一些鱼兄弟
Hey, there's some fish foIk.
-嘿，看这里！ -嘿！
- Hey, over here! - Hey! Hey! Hey, you guys!
-救命啊！ -救命啊！
- You guys, hey! HeIp! - Hey! HeIp!
-来帮帮忙！我们被 -我们困在这个缸子里！
- A IittIe heIp here! We're stuck in this-- - HeIp us out of the tank!
等等
Wait a second.
那些鱼都死了
Those fish are dead.
他会把我们怎么办？
What's he gonna do with us?
哦，不，他拿出他的邪恶工具 来拷打我们了
Oh, no, he's going for his eviI instruments of torture.
胶水？ 假眼睛？
GIue? GoogIe eyes?
他在用贝壳做一个..
He's making a humorous diorama of...
亚历山大 贝尔的盆景？
...AIexander CIam BeII?
派大星，他在杀死海洋生物 拿它们来做那些丑陋的小玩意！
Patrick, he's kiIIing sea animaIs and making them into smeIIy knickknacks.
我们可能是下一个
And I think we're next.
-你觉得是吗？ -派大星，不！
- You think so? - Patrick! No!
灯发出来的热太高了，我动不了
The heat is so intense from this Iamp that I can't move.
我也是
TeII me about it.
看上去不太妙啊，派大星
This doesn't Iook too good, Patrick.
你是说我们不能
You mean we're not gonna
拿到皇冠，拯救城市和蟹老板了？
<i>Get the crown, save the town And Mr. Krabs?</i>
我觉得我们都不能拯救我们自己了 兄弟
I don't even think we're gonna be abIe to save ourseIves, buddy.
-谢谢 -没关系
- Thanks. - Don't mention it.
看起来大家说的是真的，派大星
WeII, it Iooks Iike what everybody said about us is true, Patrick.
你是说我们很吸引人？
You mean that we're attractive?
不，是说我们都是小孩子
No, that we're just kids.
小孩干不了大事
A coupIe of kids in way over their heads.
从一开始就注定我们会失败
We were doomed from the start.
我是说，看看我们
I mean, Iook at us.
我们甚至根本没摸到皇冠
We didn't even come cIose to the crown.
我们让大家失望了
We Iet everybody down.
我们失败了
We faiIed.
贝壳城
SheII City.
是啊，我们根本没到贝壳城
Yeah, we never made it to SheII City.
贝壳城
SheII City.
对，兄弟
ExactIy, buddy.
对，我们从来没到过的地方
Yeah, the pIace we never got to.
贝壳城
SheII City.
你有点让我厌烦了，派大星
Okay, now you're starting to bum me out, Patrick.
不，看看那个标志
No, Iook at the sign.
贝壳城，海洋产品 礼品和杂货店
''SheII City. Marine gifts and sundries.''
贝壳城是个礼品店？
SheII City is a gift shop?
但是如果这个是贝壳城 那么皇冠？
But if this is SheII City, then where's the...?
-皇冠 -皇冠
- Crown. - Crown.
海王星的皇冠
Neptune's crown.
这就是贝壳城
This is SheII City.
派大星，我们成功了
Pat, we did make it.
是啊
Yeah, I guess we did.
我们还是成功了
We did aII right for a coupIe of goofbaIIs.
<i>l'm a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
<i>You're a Goofy Goober, yeah</i>
<i>We're all Goofy Goobers, yeah</i>
<i>Goofy, goofy, goober, goober, yeah</i>
海绵宝宝就这么完了？
That's the end of SpongeBob.
过来
Come here, you.
闭嘴，看看屏幕
Shut up and Iook at the screen.
鸟是对的，看啊
The bird's right. Look.
这是高菲 高伯的眼泪
It be the tear of the Goofy Goobers.
嘿，我们活过来了
Hey, we're aIive.
-我们去拿皇冠 -对
- Let's get that crown. - Right.
数到三，派大星，准备好了吗？ 一，二，三
On three, Patrick. Ready? One, two, three.
嘿，比我想象的要轻啊
Hey, it's Iighter than I thought.
怎么了？
What's happening?
我不知道啊，看！
I don't know. Look!
来啊，派大星
Come on, Patrick.
让我们把皇冠带回比奇堡
Let's get this crown back to Bikini Bottom.
-你还有那袋风吗？ -当然了
- Do you stiII have that bag of winds? - I sure do.
在这里
Here you go.
什么？
What?
没什么，没什么
Nothing. Nothing.
好吧，让我们看看说明书
Okay, Iet's go over the instructions.
看看，这里说，第一步 把袋子指向家的反方向
Let's see, it says here, ''Step one: Point bag away from home.''
-好的 -第二步，稳稳的站在地上
- Okay. - ''Step two: PIant feet firmIy on ground.''
-好的 -第三步
- Right. - ''Step three:
把绳子解开，把风放出来
Remove string from bag, reIeasing the winds.''
好的
Check.
看上去很简单吗
WeII, that seems simpIe enough.
把袋子指向家的反方向 站稳了
Point bag away from home, feet firmIy on ground,
拉绳子把风放出来
puII string, reIeasing the winds.
好的，来做一遍吧
AII right, Iet's do it for reaI.
海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
-不，不，停下！ -是我的错，对不起
- No, no, stop! - I was bad, I'm sorry!
-回来啊，袋子 -对不起，我以为
- PIease, bag. - I'm sorry, I just thought--
是我错了
It was a mistake!
哦，不，我们现在怎么回到比奇堡去？
Oh, no. How wiII we ever get back to Bikini Bottom now?
我可以带你们去
I can take you there.
-你是谁？ 我是戴维David Hasselhoff （霹雳游侠、海滩游侠影集男主角）
- Who are you? - I'm David HasseIhoff.
-万岁！ -万岁！
- Hooray! - Hooray!
那你的船在哪儿？
So where's your boat?
船？
Boat?
-走了，David Hasselhoff -下一站，比奇堡
- Go, HasseIhoff. - Next stop, Bikini Bottom.
皮老板万岁，皮老板万岁
<i>All hail Plankton. All hail Plankton.</i>
蟹老板，你知道今天是什么日子吗？
WeII, Krabs, you know what today is?
对不起，日历
Sorry about this, caIendar.
三月14日
March 1 4.
等等，不对
Wait, that's not right.
应该写着，蟹老板被烧死的日子
It shouId say ''The day that Krabs fries.''
看看谁来了
Guess who's here.
David Hasselhoff万岁！ 现在没什么能阻止我们了
Hooray for HasseIhoff! Nothing can stop us now.
屁股那里有不明物体接近
Unidentified object off the hindquarters.
看上去像是
It Iooks Iike...
大靴子
...bigger boot.
但是怎么会呢？
But how?
丹尼斯！
Dennis!
你们想念我了吧？
Did you miss me?
这里是最好的座位
This is the best seat in the house.
好吧，海王星，开始了
AII right, Neptune, Iet's get it on.
蟹老板 蟹老板 你的六天缓刑已经结束了
Eugene Krabs, your six-day reprieve is up,
你的死期到了
and it is time for you to die.
等等，我没做那件事
PIease, I didn't do it.
我也无能为力了
There is nothing eIse I can do.
你可以多给海绵宝宝和派大星一些时间
You can give SpongeBob and Patrick a IittIe more time.
除了多给海绵宝宝和派大星一些时间
Except give SpongeBob and Patrick a IittIe more time--
什么？公主，你出去
What? Mindy, wiII you butt out.
我不会让你阻碍行刑 的
I won't have you staIIing this execution.
拖延？我没有拖延啊
StaIIing? I'm not staIIing anything.
-你有 -不，我没有
- Yes, you are. - No, I'm not.
你有，你就在这样做
Yes, you are. You're doing it right now.
-我在拖延？ -对
- I'm staIIing. - Yes.
-拖延？ -阻碍
- StaIIing? - StaIIing!
-拖延？ -阻碍！
- StaIIing. - StaIIing!
哦，累死了
Oh, boy.
好了，说到哪儿了？
Now, where were we?
-派大星，跑啊 -不
- Patrick, run. - No.
我已经厌倦了逃跑
I'm tired of running.
如果我们现在逃跑，我们永远不会停止
If we run now, we'II never stop--
快跑，海绵宝宝！
Run, SpongeBob!
放松些，小子们
Take it easy back there, feIIas.
海绵宝宝，小心啊
SpongeBob, be carefuI.
来吧，孩子，放弃算了
Come on, kid, give it up.
丹尼斯从来不会失败的
Dennis aIways gets his man.
决不！
Never!
好啊，我成功了！
Yeah! I did it!
你有胆量，小孩
You got guts, kid.
不过我要把你的胆挖出来
Too bad I gotta rip them out of you.
我不知道皮老板付你多少钱
I don't know what PIankton's paying you,
不过如果你让我们走，我会 付你值得的价格
but if you Iet us go, I can make it worth your whiIe.
我的价值可不止五块
It's gonna take a Iot more than 5...
-那是什么？ -那是，先生，五块高伯元
- What is this? - That, sir, is five Goober doIIars.
可以在任何高菲 高伯店使用
LegaI tender at any participating Goofy Goober--
我还有泡泡，派对上很好玩的
I got bubbIes. Fun at parties.
我的眼睛！
My eyes.
我抓到你了，海绵宝宝
I got you, SpongeBob.
谢谢，哥们
Thanks, buddy.
谢谢
Thanks a Iot.
到此为止了
That's it.
我不会再失手了
I'm through messing around.
再见了，笨蛋们
See you Iater, fooIs.
再见
See you.
那么你觉得
So you think...
我
...I'm...
在拖延？
...staIIing.
我在哪儿，在疯子城吗？
Where am I, in Crazytown?
我受够了这些无聊的谈话了！
I have had enough of this nonsense!
你等在马车里，直到行刑结束
You are to wait in the carriage untiI the execution is done.
-但是爸爸！ -现在！
- But, Daddy-- - Now!
不，不
No, no, no!
哦，海绵宝宝，不管你在哪儿 你要快点
Oh, SpongeBob, wherever you are, you better hurry.
好的，小子们，可以下来了 比奇堡就在正下面
Okay, feIIas, this is where you get off. Bikini Bottom's directIy beIow.
但是我们没时间游下去了
But we'II never be abIe to fIoat down in time.
谁说让你们游下去了？
Who said anything about fIoating?
-启动发射程序 -这是？
<i>- lnitiating launch sequence. - What the--?</i>
-你看见了吗？ -控制系统？
- Did you see that? - The controI.
抓紧了
AII hands on deck.
还有10秒启动，9，8
<i>Ten seconds to lift-off. Nine, eight...</i>
蟹老板 蟹老板，时间到了
Eugene Krabs, the time has come...
-不 -好啊
- No. - Yes.
6，5
<i>...six, five...</i>
对你的
...for you...
-不 -好啊
- No. - Yes.
3，2
<i>...three, two...</i>
-死吧 -不
- ...to fry. - No.
-好啊
<i>- Yes. - ...one.</i>
不！
No!
干得不错，David Hasselhoff
You done good, HasseIhoff. You done--
万岁，我们成功了
Hooray! We made it.
成功了
We made it.
我的皇冠
My crown.
我的漂亮的皇冠！
My beautifuI crown!
海绵宝宝？派大星 我知道你们做的到的
SpongeBob? Patrick? I knew you couId do it.
干得好，海绵宝宝
Oh, yes. WeII done, SpongeBoob.
对不起，打断你的好戏了，皮老板
Sorry to rain on your parade, PIankton.
哦，不用担心我
Oh, don't worry about me.
我的好戏还很安全呢
My parade shaII be quite dry under my umbreIIa!
嗯？
UmbreIIa?
爸爸，不！
Daddy, no.
爸爸，是的
Daddy, yes.
皮老板万岁
<i>All hail Plankton.</i>
皮老板万岁，皮老板万岁
<i>All hail Plankton. All hail Plankton.</i>
海绵宝宝，怎么了？
SpongeBob, what happened?
-皮老板作弊了 -作弊？
- PIankton cheated. - Cheated?
等等，秃子
HoId on there, baIdy.
哦，得了吧
Oh, grow up.
你以为这是在球场上踢球吗？
What, you think this is a game of kickbaII on the pIayground?
你跟我斗是没有机会的，笨蛋
You never had a chance to defeat me, fooI.
你知道为什么吗？
And you know why?
因为你作弊？
Because you cheated?
不，不是因为我作弊 是因为我是邪恶的天才
No, not because I cheated. Because I'm an eviI genius.
你只是一个孩子
And you're just a kid.
笨小孩
A stupid kid.
我想你是对的，皮老板 我只是个孩子
I guess you're right, PIankton. I am just a kid.
当然我是对的 好了，海王星，杀了他们
Of course I'm right. Okay, Neptune, time to kiII.
你知道，我过去6天5分钟 27秒半
And you know, I've been through a Iot in the past six days,
经历了许多事情
five minutes, 27-and-a-haIf seconds.
如果我学到了什么的话
And if I've Iearned anything during that time,
那就是：你就是你自己
it's that you are who you are.
-对的，好了，海王星 -没有什么美人鱼魔法
- That's right. Okay, Neptune-- - And no amount of mermaid magic...
或者升职做经理
...or manageriaI promotion...
或者其他的事情
...or some other third thing...
能让我改变那个真实的自我
...can make me anything more than what I reaIIy am inside:
-一个小孩 -说得对
- A kid. - That's great.
-靠墙站好 -但是也没关系啊
- Now, get back against the waII. - But that's okay.
-什么？怎么了？ -因为我做到了
- What? What's going on? - Because I did
大家都认为小孩做不到的事情
what everyone said a kid couIdn't do.
我去到了贝壳城 我打败了独眼巨人
I made it to SheII City, and I beat the CycIops,
我骑上了David Hasselhoff 我把皇冠拿回来了
and I rode the HasseIhoff, and I brought the crown back.
-好吧，我们明白了 -是的，我是个孩子
- AII right, we get the point. - So, yeah, I'm a kid.
我是个笨蛋 毛头小伙子
And I'm aIso a goofbaII. And a wing nut.
是个大笨蛋
And a KnuckIehead McSpazatron!
-这是怎么了？ -但是最重要的是
- What's going on here? - But most of aII, I'm...
-安静下来，没事的 -我，我
- Okay, settIe down. Take it easy. - I'm... I'm...
到底怎么回事？
What the scaIIop?!
I'm a Goofy Goober 喔 我是高菲高伯 耶
<i>l'm a Goofy Goober</i>
You're a Goofy Goober 你是高菲高伯 耶
<i>You're a Goofy Goober</i>
We're all Goofy Goobers 我们全都是高菲高伯 耶
<i>We're all Goofy Goobers</i>
Goofy, goofy, goober, goober 高菲 高菲高伯 高伯 耶
<i>Goofy, goofy, goober, goober</i>
Put your toys away Well, all I gotta say 我要说 立刻放下你的玩具
<i>Put your toys away Well, all l gotta say</i>
When you tell me not to play I say no way 叫我不要玩 我办不到
<i>When you tell me not to play l say no way</i>
- No way! - No, no freaking way - 绝不！ - 不，不做搞怪的事
<i>- No way! - No, no freaking way</i>
I'm a kid, you say When you say I'm a kid 当你说 我只是小孩
<i>l'm a kid, you say When you say l'm a kid</i>
I say, "Say it again" And then I say thanks 你有种再说一次！ 但我却要感谢你
<i>l say, ''Say it again'' And then l say thanks</i>
- Thanks! - Thank you very much 感谢你！
<i>- Thanks! - Thank you very much</i>
So if you're thinking That you'd like to be like me 如果你只这么想， 那你并不如我，你得学我
<i>So if you're thinking That you'd like to be like me</i>
Go ahead and try The kid inside will set you free 放手一博去尝试 心中的那个小孩会拯救你
<i>Go ahead and try The kid inside will set you free</i>
I'm a Goofy Goober 喔 我是高菲高伯 耶
<i>l'm a Goofy Goober</i>
是怎么了？
What's happening?
他的舞步不错，但是我说了算！
His dance moves are impressive, but I'm in controI.
-抓住他！ -皮老板万岁！
<i>- Seize him! - All hail Plankton.</i>
我自由了，我自由了！
I'm free. I've been freed!
什么？
What?
不！
No!
我的宝贵的头盔啊！
My precious heImets!
他的歌声太正义了
His chops are too righteous.
头盔没法抵抗这种程度的摇滚乐
The heImets can't handIe this IeveI of rock 'n' roII.
老婆，快采取行动啊
Karen, do something.
老婆？
Karen?
好吧，结束了
AII right, that's the Iast straw.
海王星，我命令你
Neptune, I command you to...
-在这里，爸爸 -我得快点走
- Here you go, Daddy. - I better get out of here.
看，是那个巫师救了我们
Look, it's the wizard who saved us.
滚开，笨蛋
Out of my way, fooIs.
哦，我是开玩笑的
Come on, I was just kidding.
哦，你们知道的，不是吗？
Come on, you guys knew that, didn't you?
头盔和皮老板大型纪念碑...
With the heImets and the big monuments...
很有趣不是吗？
Wasn't that hiIarious, everybody?
我会报仇的！
I wiII destroy aII of you!
公主，我得承认，你是对的
WeII, Mindy, I have to admit, you were right.
妳对所有海洋生物的怜悯
Your compassion for these sea creatures
妳是最值得敬佩的
proved a most admirabIe trait.
没有妳，我肯定再也见不到我的 宝贵的皇冠了
Without it, I wouId have never again seen my beIoved crown.
我想你将来会是海洋里的伟大君主的
I think you're going to make a fine ruIer of the sea one day.
-我们回家吧 -爸爸
- Now, Iet's go home. - Daddy,
你忘了什么了吗？
haven't you forgotten something?
什么？哦，对
What? Oh, yeah.
蟹老板 我忘了解冻你
Eugene Krabs, I forgot to unfreeze you.
什么？
What the--?
哦，我设定成男孩档了
I guess I had it set to ''reaI boy'' ending.
对不起，我不应该把你冻起来的 蟹老板
Oh, I'm sorry for faIseIy freezing you, Krabs.
我应该说，先生，你非常幸运
And may I say, sir, you are a very Iucky feIIow
你的员工有这么一个勇敢而忠心的
to have in your empIoy such a brave, faithfuI
英雄般的小伙子
and heroic young Iad.
-他在哪儿？ -我在这里
- Where is he, anyway? - I'm up here.
我来吧
I'm on it.
走上前去，拥抱他吧，蟹老板
Go to him now, Krabs. Embrace him.
海绵宝宝，好小子，真对不起 我不该怀疑你
SpongeBob, me boy, I'm sorry I ever doubted you.
我不会再犯这个错误了
That's a mistake I won't make again.
哦，蟹老板，你太过奖了
Oh, Mr. Krabs, you oId soft-serve.
现在，海绵宝宝，我要做一件事
And now, SpongeBob, I'm gonna do something
一件我6天前就应该做的事
that I shouId've done six days ago.
章鱼哥先生，请到这里来
Mr. Squidward, front and centre, pIease.
我想我们都知道谁真正有资格 戴上这个经理的胸针
I think we aII know who rightfuIIy deserves to wear that manager pin.
我完全同意，先生
I couIdn't agree more, sir.
海绵宝宝万岁！
Hooray for SpongeBob!
等等，大家
Wait a second, everybody.
我首先要说一件事
There's something I need to say first.
我只是不知道该如何说起
I just don't know how to put it.
我知道是什么
I think I know what it is.
经过你的惊心动魄的旅程
After going on your Iife-changing journey,
你现在意识到了你并不 想要你原来一直想要的东西
you now reaIize you don't want what you thought you wanted.
你真正想要的，一直在你的心底里
What you reaIIy wanted was inside you aII aIong.
你疯了吗？我只是想说你的 裤子拉链没拉上！
Are you crazy? I was just gonna teII you that your fIy is down.
经理！这是我一辈子最高兴的一天！
Manager! This is the greatest day of my Iife!
你知道，戴维 哈斯霍夫是个伟大的 艺术家
You know, David HasseIhoff is a great artist.
对不起，先生
Excuse me, sir.
你们得离开了
You foIks have to Ieave.
什么？你敢再说一遍
What? Say that again, if you dare.
你们得离开了
You foIks have to Ieave.
好吧
Okay.